<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Sourabh Misal</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Sourabh Misal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> Drivn : Autonomous Navigation Kit for existing Battery Operated Pallet Trucks (BOPTs)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/drivn_auto_nav_kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/drivn_auto_nav_kit/</guid>
      <description>Description Developed an autonomous navigation kit for existing Battery-Operated Pallet Trucks (BOPTs) as part of Flux Auto&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive warehouse automation solution, following the guidelines of IEC 61508 which is Functional Safety of Electrical/Electronic/Programmable Electronic Safety-related Systems.&#xA;Key Technologies and Skills Communication Protocols :&#xA;CANopen Protocol : Integrated CANopen for robust communication among submodules of the modularized embedded system architecture. Developed custom CANopen nodes for various components, ensuring seamless interaction with the vehicle’s existing CAN bus and its subsystems and facilitating modular and scalable firmware architecture Embedded Communication Protocols : Developed low-level drivers for I2C, CAN, UART, and USB using HAL APIs and libraries provided by silicon vendors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Vector : Autonomous Navigation Kit for existing Reach Trucks (RTs)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/vector_auto_nav_kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/vector_auto_nav_kit/</guid>
      <description>Description Developed an autonomous navigation kit for existing Reach Trucks (RTs) as part of Flux Auto&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive warehouse automation solution, following the guidelines of IEC 61508 which is Functional Safety of Electrical/Electronic/Programmable Electronic Safety-related Systems.&#xA;Key Technologies and Skills Communication Protocols :&#xA;CANopen Protocol : Integrated CANopen for robust communication among submodules of the modularized embedded system architecture. Developed custom CANopen nodes for various components, ensuring seamless interaction with the vehicle’s existing CAN bus and its subsystems and facilitating modular and scalable firmware architecture Embedded Communication Protocols : Developed low-level drivers for I2C, CAN, UART, and USB using HAL APIs and libraries provided by silicon vendors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Indoor Positioning System (IPS) Using ESP32, MQTT and Bluetooth: </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/ips_esp32_ble_mqtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/ips_esp32_ble_mqtt/</guid>
      <description>Description This was the final year project of the undergraduate course in electronics and communication engineering. Please find the full description in this Github Link :! This was also published as a research paper :- DOI: 10.1109/ICCMC48092.2020.ICCMC-00015 Hardware used are ESP32 Microcontrollers, Bluetooth Low Energy beacon Technology used is Message Queing Telemetry Transport Trilateration algorithm is made to run on the received RSSI values and position is determined. The firmware and the positioning algorithm were written on the C/C++ and ReactJS .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Ceres : Autonomous Navigation Kit for Tractors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/ceres_auto_nav_kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/ceres_auto_nav_kit/</guid>
      <description>Description Designed and implemented embedded control systems of autonomous navigation kit for tractors as part of Flux Auto&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive agricultural automation solution, following the guidelines of ISO 18497 and 25119-1 which is Agricultural machinery and tractors — Safety of partially automated, semi-autonomous and autonomous machinery&#xA;Key Technologies and Skills Communication Protocols :&#xA;CANopen Protocol : Integrated CANopen for robust communication among submodules of the modularized embedded system architecture. Developed custom CANopen nodes for various components, ensuring seamless interaction with the vehicle’s existing CAN bus and its subsystems and facilitating modular and scalable firmware architecture Embedded Communication Protocols : Developed low-level drivers for I2C, CAN, UART, and USB using HAL APIs and libraries provided by silicon vendors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Table Tennis Shooting Robot </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/table_tennis_shooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/table_tennis_shooting/</guid>
      <description>Description This was the project done at my first internship after my undergraduate course in electronics and communication engineering. Please have a look at the project using this Link Wrote and optimized firmware which provides spin capability for the robot. Wrote and optimized firmware for motor control systems of various motors used, including BLDC, Stepper and Servo Motor. Learnt PCB Designing and optimized design of control board using EasyEDA and KiCad Worked on a feedback loop system using IR sensor for the robot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Prototype of Wearable Cursor Control </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/wearable_cursor_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/wearable_cursor_control/</guid>
      <description>Description This was a hobby project done for emulating mouse control using hand gestures. Please have a look at the link for seeing the project in action The motivation was to create a more seamless user experience for the human-computer interaction. The hand gestures were picked up by the MPU6050 IC which is a three-axis accelerometer and three-axis gyroscope Micro Electro-mechanical system (MEMS). Wrote and optimized firmware which provides spin capability for the robot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hardware of Home Automation system </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/home_automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/home_automation/</guid>
      <description>Description Link : https://www.youtube.com/watch?si=eiIdjnngemfgRDL1&amp;amp;v=C3e-fgLwdl8&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be Wrote and optimized firmware which provides spin capability for the robot. Learnt PCB Designing and optimized design of control board using EasyEDA and KiCad Debugging issues of the robot Worked on a feedback loop system using IR sensor for the robot. Worked on system to detect bounce using piezo-electric sensors. Learnt about improvements in designing the product and optimization of embedded software. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Prototype of Home service robot in virtual world using TurtleBot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/home_service_robot_proto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/home_service_robot_proto/</guid>
      <description>Description This project was done with the aim of demonstrating the knowledge of Simultaneous Localization and Mapping (SLAM) and Navigation Goal mode of a robot. I had done the simulation setup on gazebo for interfacing robot with different ROS packages, some of which are official ROS packages and others are packages that are created. The navigation of robot to specified pick-up and drop-off zones within the Gazebo world using localization is done using AMCL and trajectory planning through ROS Navigation stack, which relies on Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s algorithm.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
